(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Revival -角巻わため生誕祭2024-
Revival: Tsunomaki Watame's Birthday Celebration 2024
重大告知あり
Major announcement included!
2024.06.06(Thu) 21:00START
2024.06.06 (Thu) 21:00 START
遠い。
Far away.
わたしが目指す場所は、
The place I am aiming for,
あまりにも遠い。
is far too distant.
歩いて、
Walking,
歩いて、歩いて、歩いて、
Walking, walking, walking,
バカげた夢だろうか。
Is it a foolish dream?
諦める理由なら
If it's reasons to give up,
過去に捨ててきた
I've thrown them away in the past.
僕だけの栄光路を
The path of glory only for me,
証明したいんだ。
I want to prove it.
不穏な未来は
The unsettling future,
ギラついた目で見睨む
I'll glare at it with sharp eyes.
何者でもない僕らの欠片
Fragments of us, who are nobody.
「歌いたくてホロライブに来たんだよ。」
"I came to Hololive because I wanted to sing."
#角巻わため生誕祭2024
#TsunomakiWatameBirthday2024
教えて 教えてよ
Tell me, oh tell me
その仕組みを
The way it works
僕の中に
Inside of me
誰かいるの？
Is there someone else?
壊れた 壊れたよ
I'm broken, so broken
この世界で
Within this world
君が笑う
You're laughing
何も見えずに
Without seeing a thing
unravel
作詞・作曲 TK
Lyrics/Composition: TK
壊れた僕なんてさ
As for the broken me
息を止めて
Holding my breath
ほどけない もう ほどけないよ
Can't unravel, can't unravel anymore
真実さえ
Not even the truth
freeze
壊せる 壊せない
Can break, can't break
狂える 狂えない
Can go mad, can't go mad
あなたを見つけて
Finding you
揺れた歪んだ世界にだんだん僕は
In a shaken, distorted world, I gradually...
透き通って見えなくなって
Become transparent and invisible
見つけないで 僕のことを
Don't find me
見つめないで
Don't look at me
誰かが描いた世界の中で
In a world someone else depicted
あなたを傷つけたくはないよ
I don't want to hurt you
覚えていて
Remember me
僕のことを
My existence
鮮やかなまま
Vividly
無限に広がる孤独が絡まる
An infinitely expanding solitude entangles me
無邪気に笑った記憶が刺さって
Memories of innocent laughter pierce through
動けない 動けない
Can't move, can't move
動けない 動けないよ
Can't move, I can't move
unravel!
変わってしまった 変えられなかった
I have changed, I couldn't be changed
二つが絡まる 二人が滅びる
The two entangle, the two perish
壊せる 壊せない 狂える 狂えない
Can break, can't break, can go mad, can't go mad
あなたを汚せないよ
I won't let you be defiled
揺れた歪んだ世界にだんだん僕は
In a shaken, distorted world, I gradually...
透き通って見えなくなって
Become transparent and invisible
見つけないで 僕のことを
Don't find me
見つめないで
Don't look at me
誰かが仕組んだ孤独な罠に
In a lonely trap someone set up
未来がほどけてしまう前に
Before the future unraveled
思い出して
Remember me
僕のことを
My existence
鮮やかなまま
Vividly
忘れないで
Don't forget
変わってしまったことにパラライズ
Paralyzed by the fact that things have changed
変えられないことだらけパラダイス
A paradise full of unchangeable things
覚えていて
Remember me
僕のことを
My existence
教えて...
Tell me...
僕の中に
Inside of me
誰かいるの？
Is there someone else?
悪魔の子
作詞・作曲 ヒグチアイ
Akuma no Ko
Lyrics/Composition: Higuchi Ai
鉄の玉が正義の証明
An iron ball is proof of justice
貫けば英雄に近づいた
If you pierce through, you come closer to a hero
その目を閉じて触れてみれば
If you close your eyes and touch it
同じ形 同じ体温の悪魔
It's a devil with the same shape and warmth
僕はダメであいつはいいの？
Why is it bad for me but okay for them?
そこに壁があっただけなのに
Even though there was just a wall there
生まれてしまった運命嘆くな
Don't lament the fate you were born into
僕らはみんな自由なんだから
Because we are all free
鳥のように羽があれば
If I had wings like a bird
どこへだって行けるけど
I could go anywhere
帰る場所がなければきっと
But if I have no place to return to
どこへも行けない
I surely can't go anywhere
ただ　ただ　生きるのは嫌だ
Just, just living is not enough...
世界は残酷だ
The world is cruel.
それでも君を愛すよ
Even so, I will love you.
何を犠牲にしても
No matter what I sacrifice.
それでも君を守るよ
Even so, I will protect you.
間違いだとしても　疑ったりしない
Even if it's a mistake, I won't doubt it.
正しさとは自分のこと　強く信じることだ
Righteousness is believing in yourself strongly.
鉄の雨が降り散る情景　テレビの中映画に見えたんだ
The scene of iron rain falling looked like a movie on TV.
戦争なんて愚かな凶暴　関係ない知らない国の話
War is a foolish brutality, a story from an unknown country unrelated to me.
それなら何であいつに組んで　黒い気持ち隠しきれないわけ
Then why do I resent them, unable to hide these dark feelings?
説明だってできやしないんだ　僕らはなんて矛盾ばっかなんだ
I can't even explain it; we are so full of contradictions.
この言葉も訳されれば　本当の意味は伝わらない
If these words are translated, their true meaning won't get through.
信じるのはその目を開けて　触れた世界だけ
Believe only in the world you touched with your eyes wide open.
ただ　ただ　生きるのは嫌だ
Just, just living is not enough...
世界は残酷だ
The world is cruel.
それでも君を愛すよ
Even so, I will love you.
何を犠牲にしても
No matter what I sacrifice.
それでも君を守るよ
Even so, I will protect you.
選んだ人の影　捨てたものの屍
The shadows of those chosen, the corpses of things discarded.
気づいたんだ自分の中　育つのは悪魔の子
I realized that growing inside of me is a child of the devil.
正義の裏犠牲の中　心には悪魔の子
Behind justice, within sacrifice, there is a child of the devil in my heart.
聞いてくれてありがとう！
Thank you for listening!
そして、角巻わため生誕祭2024
And, to everyone who came to see...
Revivalを見に来てくれてありがとうございます！
...Tsunomaki Watame's 2024 Birthday Celebration "Revival", thank you so much!
今日でなんとわためは...
Today, Watame is actually...
8歳になりましたー！イエーイ！
...turning 8 years old! Yay!
みんなの応援があってこそ迎えられた8歳だと思います。
I believe I was able to reach age 8 only because of everyone's support.
あー、おめでとう、ありがとう。いっぱいありがとうございます。
Ah, "congratulations", thank you. Thank you so much.
もう本当にわためをいつも支えてくれて
Really, I can't thank you enough...
感謝してもしきれないぐらいです。本当にありがとう。
...for always supporting Watame. Thank you so much.
今日はね、ちょっと暗めの闇深な曲から始まりましたが
We started today with a somewhat dark and deep song...
見てくれているみんなと、そしてゲストのみんなと一緒に
...but I want to explore all kinds of music together with everyone watching...
さらにいろんな音楽を巡って
...and with all of our guests...
そして、Revivalしていきたいと思いますので
...and I want to continue to "Revival"...
今日は素敵なライブにしましょう！
...so let's make today a wonderful live!
あ、そういえば、このモニター、すごかったでしょう？
Oh, by the way, that monitor was amazing, right?
今真っ暗だけどね。
Though it's pitch black now.
これ、途中で変身したんだけどさ
It transformed earlier...
あと、2回、いや、3回、いや、4回...
...and it will transform another 2 times, no, 3 times, no, 4 times...
何回だったかな？
...how many times was it?
このモニターが変形するので、ぜひバシバシスクショを撮ってほしいなと思います。
Since this monitor changes shape, I want you to take lots of screenshots.
そして、#角巻わため生誕祭2024 で
Also, I'd be happy if you post a lot...
たくさんポストもしていただけると嬉しいです！
...using the hashtag #TsunomakiWatameBirthday2024!
ラストには告知
There will be an announcement at the end...
そして、その後はメン限ライブもありますので
...followed by a members-only live...
最後までぜひ楽しんでいってください！
...so please enjoy until the very end!
次の曲に...
To the next song...
行ってもいいかな？
Can I go?
いいかな？
Can I?
いいよー！
Okay!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
では、次は...
Now, next is...
ロリなあの曲...
That loli song...
行きましょう！
Let's go!
粛聖!! ロリ神レクイエム☆
Sainted!! Loli God Requiem☆
ロリロリ神降臨
Loli loli god's descent
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
If you ring the bell, it's just like this
それが救済のレクイエム
That is the requiem of salvation
せーの、触ったな逮捕
Ready, set, touched! Arrested!
獄中で点呼
Roll call in prison
一二三四
One, two, three, four
ハァ？
Huh?
ごめんなさいが聞こえない
I can't hear your "I'm sorry"
粛聖ロリ神レクイエム
Sainted Loli God Requiem
将来はお前なんかに好かれたくない
In the future, I don't want to be liked by someone like you
泥水吸って口を洗え
Drink mud water and wash your mouth
反省しててああ、ね
Reflect on it, ah, right?
さあ、お巡りさん連れて行って
Now, Mr. Police Officer, take him away
妄想しか取り柄のない
With nothing but delusions
可哀想な人
A pitiful person
その姿を親に見せられますか？
Can you show that appearance to your parents?
はぁ、ありがとう。お疲れ様です。
Haa, thank you. Good job.
ロリロリ神降臨
Loli loli god's descent
マジやべえ奴らに用心
Beware of really dangerous guys
まともじゃないなら
If you're not normal
早く消えてください
Please disappear quickly
ラブリーロリロリ神降臨
Lovely loli loli god's descent
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
If you ring the bell, it's just like this
とっても優しくて
A very kind and...
素敵なお兄ちゃん
...wonderful big brother
楽園でほらねんねしな
Now, go sleep in paradise
世の中にはこんな気持ち悪い人たちが跋扈しているんですよ
In this world, such disgusting people are running rampant
みんな粛清してあげますよ
I'll purge everyone for you
せーの、触ったな逮捕
Ready, set, touched! Arrested!
獄中で面会
Meeting in prison
一二三四
One, two, three, four
ハァ？
Huh?
ごめんなさいが聞こえない
I can't hear your "I'm sorry"
粛聖ロリ神レクイエム
Sainted Loli God Requiem
はい、獄中にいる皆さん、刑務所ファンミーティングのお時間です！
Yes, everyone in prison, it's time for the prison fan meeting!
その腐り切った耳をゴリゴリ掻き穿ってよく聞いてくださいね
Please scrape out those rotten ears and listen carefully
ザコ
Weakling
キモキモ
Gross-gross
ザコ
Weakling
うるさい
Noisy
ザコ
Weakling
反省してますか？
Are you reflecting?
嫌いです
I hate you
かわいそう
Pitiful
ダサ
Uncool
弱
Weak
みっともない
Unsightly
箸にも棒にもお兄ちゃん
Neither head nor tail, big brother
もう希望もないゴミだお前ら
You guys are just hopeless trash
汚物消毒百番
Filth disinfection No. 100
固有結界ごっつぁんと！
Reality Marble, thank you for the meal!
粛聖!!
Sainted!!
ういビーム!!
Ui Beam!!
やめろー！はなせー！
Stop! Let me go!
怒りの日、聖なる怒り
Day of wrath, holy anger
血の雨が降り注ぐ
Rain of blood pours down
愚かな幼女狂の骨の髄まで浄化する一筋の光
A single beam of light that purifies the foolish loli-con to the bone
それがういビームなのです
That is the Ui Beam
あー全然許さんが
Ah, I don't forgive you at all, though
ああ、この世の醜さを集めて描いてみるよ
Ah, I'll try drawing by gathering the ugliness of this world
真っ白なキャンバスが汚れて泣いている
The pure white canvas is dirty and crying
本当降臨の美少女は
Truly descended beautiful girl is...
さわってもいいかも？
...maybe it's okay to touch?
楽園などないから
Because there is no such thing as paradise
大きなお友達のみんなへ！
To all the "big friends"!
お前らが打ち込んでいる虚無には何の味があるの？
What kind of flavor is there in the void you guys are devoted to?
ねえ教えてよ
Hey, tell me
わため全然わかんないんだ
Watame doesn't understand at all
ロリロリ神降臨
Loli loli god's descent
さよなら笑顔でバイバイ
Goodbye with a smile, bye-bye
ピリオドをどうぞ
Please have a period
この手で押してあげよう
I'll push it with this hand
ラブリーロリロリ神降臨
Lovely loli loli god's descent
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
If you ring the bell, it's just like this
とっても優しくて
A very kind and...
素敵なお兄ちゃん
...wonderful big brother
楽園でほら
In paradise, see
ねんねしな
Go sleep
それが救済の
That is the...
レクイエム
...requiem
せーの、触ったな逮捕
Ready, set, touched! Arrested!
獄中で点呼
Roll call in prison
一二三四
One, two, three, four
ハァ？
Huh?
ハァ？(ﾟДﾟ)
Huh? (ﾟДﾟ)
ごめんなさいが聞こえない
I can't hear your "I'm sorry"
えー！
Eeeh!
粛聖ロリ神レクイエム
Sainted Loli God Requiem
本当に気持ち悪い
Truly disgusting
こちら、幸福安心委員会です。
This is the Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee.
作詞：鳥居羊　作曲：うたたP
Lyrics: Torii Hitsuji, Composition: UtataP
どうして　みんなが幸せなの？
Why is everyone so happy?
この世界のことが
About this world
聞きたいって
They say they want to hear
知りたいって
They say they want to know
水辺の公園で
In the park by the water
みんなが耳をすませて
Everyone listens closely
ワクワクするね
It's exciting, isn't it?
ええ、オンディーヌの
Yes, Undine's...
ワクワクするね
It's exciting, isn't it?
Ａ Ｏ Ｎ Ｄ Ｉ Ｉ Ｎ Ｏ
A O N D I I N O
ハイハイ！
High, high!
さぁさぁ皆さん　教えてあげます
Come now, everyone, I'll tell you
みんなが気になってること　疑問に思ってること
The things you're curious about, the things you're wondering
全部　教えてあげます
I'll tell you everything
ええ、皆さんが幸福なのは義務なんです
Yes, it's your duty to be happy
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
義務ですよ、果たしてますか？
It's a duty, are you fulfilling it?
我々幸福安心委員会は
We, the Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee
皆様の幸せを願い、そして支えます
Wish for and support everyone's happiness
幸福なのは義務なんです
It's a duty to be happy
幸せですか？　義務ですよ
Are you happy? It's a duty
幸福なのは義務なんです
It's a duty to be happy
幸せですか？　義務ですよ
Are you happy? It's a duty
ですから、安心して義務を果たすように
So, please fulfill your duty with peace of mind
皆様の幸せが　我々も幸せ
Your happiness is our happiness too
幸せですか？　義務ですよ
Are you happy? It's a duty
果たしてますか？
Are you fulfilling it?
幸せじゃないなら……
If you aren't happy...
絞首 斬首 銃殺 釜茹で 溺死 電気 火あぶり
Hanging, beheading, shooting, boiling, drowning, electrocution, burning
埋め 薬殺 石打ち 鋸挽き 磔
Burial, lethal injection, stoning, sawing, crucifixion
好きなの、選んでね
Choose whichever you like
ハイハイ！
High, high!
さぁさぁ皆さん　幸せだけが満ちてます
Come now, everyone, only happiness fills the air
不安とか不満　何一つないでしょう？
Anxiety or dissatisfaction, there's not a single thing, right?
こわ、こわいわ　幸せすぎてこわいわ
Scary, it's scary. It's so happy it's scary
ほんとうに　みんなが幸せなの？
Is everyone really happy?
この世界の「外」へ
To the "outside" of this world
行きたいって
They say they want to go
逃げたいって
They say they want to escape
水辺の公園で
In the park by the water
みんなが耳をふさいで
Everyone covers their ears
ビクビクしてた
They were trembling
ええ、オンディーヌね
Yes, it's Undine
ビクビクしてた
They were trembling
Ａ Ｏ Ｎ Ｄ Ｉ Ｉ Ｎ Ｅ
A O N D I I N E
ハイハイ！
High, high!
さぁさぁ皆さん　死にました
Come now, everyone, they died
オンディーヌを振った騎士は　死にました
The knight who rejected Undine died
葬儀に出るなよ　向こうに並べ
Don't go to the funeral, line up over there
それ以外は幸せに暮らせ
Otherwise, live happily
以上！
That's all!
幸福なのは義務なんです
It's a duty to be happy
幸せですか？　義務ですよ
Are you happy? It's a duty
幸福なのは義務なんです
It's a duty to be happy
幸せですか？　義務ですよ
Are you happy? It's a duty
義務なんです
It's a duty
義務ですよ
義務なんです
It's a duty
幸福なのは義務なんです
It's a duty to be happy
義務なんです
It's a duty
義務ですよ
義務なんです
It's a duty
幸せじゃないなら……　死ね
If you aren't happy... die
mumei / 作詞・作曲・編曲：TKN
mumei / Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: TKN
忘れてしまった　ことだけを覚えている
I only remember the things I've forgotten
ぽっかりと空いた　穴の先で君と出会った
I met you beyond the gaping hole
名前も顔も分からない君なんだか
Your name and face, I don't know them, but somehow...
懐かしいような気がした
I felt like I missed you
互いに穴を埋めてゆくように
As if filling each other's holes
ふざけ合って　笑い合って
Messing around, laughing together
セカイ　愛のどこかにいる君のため
World, for you, who is somewhere in love
イマ　生きているよ僕ら
Now, we are living
無名のまま
Still nameless
例えばこれが　映し出された幻でも
Even if this is just a projected illusion
確かに感じる　今君がそこにいること
I certainly feel that you are there now
名前も顔も分からない君
Your name and face, I don't know them
サヨナラしてしまえば終わりだ
If we say goodbye, it's over
君がいなきゃ穴は大きくなる
Without you, the hole will grow larger
構わないさ　すぐ見つかる
I don't mind, I'll find you soon
セカイ　愛のどこかにいる君はどこ
World, where are you, who is somewhere in love
イマ　ここにいるよ私
Now, I am here
無名
Mumei
辺りは一面真っ暗な世界　真っ逆さまに落ちていく
The surroundings are a pitch-black world, falling headfirst
無名だからこの世界には　忘れられ消えちゃうの
Because I'm nameless, in this world, I'll be forgotten and disappear
それでも君が求めるのなら　この胸に空いた穴に今
Still, if you wish for it, now in this hole in my chest
響け私私を通り抜け　地の果てまで今君のもとへと行く
Resonate through me, pass through me, to the ends of the earth, I'll go to you now
セカイ　愛のどこかにいる君のため
World, for you, who is somewhere in love
イマ　生きていくよ私
Now, I will live on
無名のまま
Still nameless
名前のない怪物
The Nameless Monster
震えてるわ
It's shaking
咲き死んだみたい
It looks like it bloomed and died
煉瓦の病棟で
In the brick ward
うまく歌えなくて
I couldn't sing well
霧煙る夜
A sheer forest
浮かび上がった赤い月
A floating red moon
ほら見て私を
Hey, look at me
目をそらさないで
Don't look away
黒い鉄格子のなかで
Inside the black iron bars...
私は生まれてきたんだ
...I was born
悪意の代償を願い
Wishing for the price of malice...
望むがままにおまえに
...as I please, to you
さあ与えよう正義を
Now, I shall grant you justice
壊して壊される前に
Destroying it before it gets destroyed
因果の代償払い
Paying the price of karma...
共に行こう名前のない怪物
...let's go together, the nameless monster
祈りがしてる
I'm praying
鉄条網もろくて
The barbed wire is fragile
思い出せないの
I can't remember
あの日の旋律
The melody of that day
雨はまだやまない
The rain still hasn't stopped
何も見えないの
I can't see anything
ほら見てこんなに
Look, like this...
大きくなったの
...it has grown so big
黒い雨降らせこの空
Making the black rain fall from this sky...
私は望まれないもの
...I am the unwanted one
ひび割れた音色で愛す
Loving with a cracked tone...
土台の傍観者たちに
...the ground-dwelling bystanders
さあ今ふるえ正義を
Now, tremble, justice...
消せない傷抱きしめて
...hugging the indelible wounds
この体を入れ
Accepting this body...
共に行こう名前のない怪物
...let's go together, the nameless monster
ああ神は
Ah, God is...
告げる
...telling
真の
The true...
世界を
...world
黒い鉄格子のなかで
Inside the black iron bars...
私は生まれてきたんだ
...I was born
悪意の代償を願い
Wishing for the price of malice...
望むがままにおまえに
...as I please, to you
さあ与えよう正義を
Now, I shall grant you justice
壊して壊される前に
Destroying it before it gets destroyed
因果の代償払い
Paying the price of karma...
報いよう名前のない怪物
...let's pay it back, the nameless monster
黒い雨降らせこの空
Making the black rain fall from this sky...
私は望まれないもの
...I am the unwanted one
ひび割れた音色で愛す
Loving with a cracked tone...
土台の傍観者たちに
...the ground-dwelling bystanders
さあ今ふるえ正義を
Now, tremble, justice...
消せない傷抱きしめて
Hugging the indelible wounds
この体を受け入れ
Accepting this body...
共に行こう名前のない怪物
...let's go together, the nameless monster
名前のない怪物
The Nameless Monster
静寂に響けよ My howling
Echo through the silence, my howling
Howling
滔々と流れてく風景
A landscape that flows on and on
刹那的な日々の中で
Within these fleeting days
差し伸べられた手は優しく
The hand reached out to me was kind
鼓動に滴る微熱の予感
A premonition of a slight fever dripping into my heartbeat
風に逆らう そう生きてきたから
Fighting against the wind, because that's how I've lived
君に会って気づく
Meeting you, I realize
もう一人じゃない
I'm not alone anymore
咆哮 瞬きは 咆哮 月へ響く
A howl, a flicker, a howl echoes to the moon
爪弾く未知 艱難の群れ 共に嘆く夜
A strummed unknown, a host of hardships, a night we grieve together
遠く伝播する想いは心強くする
Sentiments propagating far and wide make me stronger
付け入るなよ 後ろに君がいるから
Don't you dare try anything, because you're behind me
私は迷わない 光射す道へ
I won't hesitate on the path toward the light
無力だから仲間を求め
Because I'm powerless, I seek companions
凍えるから火を灯して
Because I'm freezing, I light a fire
変化と共に進化してく
Evolving along with the changes
この結末は誰も知らない
No one knows how this ends
君を信じる そう決めているから
I believe in you, because that's what I've decided
どんな異常 非情も
Any anomaly, any heartlessness
乗り越えられるよ
I can overcome them all
月光 今宵に唯一 凛と咲く花
Moonlight, the only flower blooming gallantly tonight
恐れなのか憧れなのか 向かい合う夜空
Is it fear, or is it longing? Facing the night sky
大地を駆け抜ける 私と君が作り出す
Dashing across the earth, you and I create
この物語 多重な未来じゃない
This story, it's not some multiple future
沸き立つ情熱 この声に乗せよう
Let's put our surging passion into this voice
空を飛ぶ羽根なくても
Even without wings to fly through the sky
手を繋げられたから
Because we were able to hold hands
この運命を選んだ
I chose this fate
連動する遠吠えは静寂に響いて
Our linked howls echo through the silence
何度も何度も その絆を確かめあった
Time and time again, we confirmed that bond
嗚呼 瞬きは 咆哮 月へ響く
Ah, a flicker, a howl echoes to the moon
爪弾く未知 艱難の群れ 共に嘆く夜
A strummed unknown, a host of hardships, a night we grieve together
遠く伝播する想いは心強くする
Sentiments propagating far and wide make me stronger
共に行こうよ 傍に君がいるから
Let's go together, because you're by my side
私は迷わない 光射す道へ
I won't hesitate on the path toward the light
Listen to my howling
狼が止まることはない
The wolf will never stop
PSYCHO
Hey, unhappy? 弱腰 楽園
Hey, unhappy? Spineless paradise
into this order 吸い込まれていく
Sucked into this order
地球もそろそろ 縄張り疲れ
The Earth is getting tired of territory wars too
飽きちゃったね いつまで転がろう
Bored of it all, how long shall we keep rolling?
輪廻転生 繰り返される営み
Samsara, the recurring cycle of life
つまんない 正すと更生
Boring, if you fix it, it's rehabilitation
聖母 ごちゃ混ぜ 混沌召し上がれ
Virgin Mary, all mixed up, feast on the chaos
悪意が僕を 魅了して止まない
Malice fascinates me incessantly
出すな その手は
Don't reach out that hand.
吐いた 綺麗に
I spat it out, so beautifully.
罪のオムサービス 言葉に溺れ
Sinful omuservice, drowning in words.
愛したいな 活かしたいな
I want to love, I want to keep alive.
壊したいな 会いたいな
I want to break, I want to meet.
世界が僕らを嫌うなら
If the world hates us...
火だるま 目を獲って喰らう
On fire, I'll take out your eyes and eat them.
ワン、ツー さっきまでしがみついてたガム
One, two, the gum I was clinging onto until just now.
ブルー 赤い目して あどけなさが
Blue, with red eyes, your innocence...
残酷 天使のツラして
Cruel, wearing an angel's face,
憂いながらも手遊んだ
I played even while grieving.
弱者 敗者 踏みつけて
Trampling on the weak, the losers,
サイコ！サイコ！
Psycho! Psycho!
治療してよ
Treat me.
カルテはめちゃくちゃ
My medical chart is a mess.
刺して、ほら その細い針
Stab me, look, with that thin needle.
不可解 痛い 鳴らなく響いても
Inexplicable, painful, even if it echoes without ringing.
遵守 溶けて証拠 これが麻薬でしょ
Compliance, melting proof, this must be a drug.
毒に染まる愛 情熱的な恋
Love stained in poison, a passionate love.
僕はどこまで行けるのか
How far can I go?
醜いの 汚いの
It's ugly, it's dirty,
美しいの 素晴らしいの
It's beautiful, it's wonderful,
時代よ 僕を受け止めて
Era, accept me!
私、さっきも聞いたよ
I heard it just now, too.
ドロドロの ストレス社会
A muddy, stressful society.
僕はひたすらこの楽園を生き抜いてやろう
I'll just survive in this paradise.
火だるま 目を獲って喰らう
On fire, I'll take out your eyes and eat them.
ワン、ツー さっきまでしがみついてたガム
One, two, the gum I was clinging onto until just now.
ブルー 赤い目して 血しぶき踊れ
Blue, with red eyes, let the blood spray dance.
残酷 天使のツラして 憂いながらも手遊んだ
Cruel, wearing an angel's face, I played even while grieving.
僕がいつか消えるまで
Until I disappear someday,
ただ遊んで
...just play.
弱者 敗者 踏みつけて
Trampling on the weak, the losers,
サイコ！サイコ！
Psycho! Psycho!
When you look up at the night sky, what do you see?
The glowing beauty in the twilight, no mystery.
Now watch me set the scene and light it all up.
When the time has come I will be rising high.
Glory for me like a red light whenever you see.
My shine!
Oh, you can't deny!
It's pulling you in like gravity.
You will be bowing on your knees, yeah.
Pulling you in close to me.
Watch my glory, am I following or leading the high tide?
My reign will never stop.
The time begins so right to hit the top.
Let my power ignite.
Following or leading the high tide.
I can be a bright enigma, it's no surprise.
But you'll give in to the brilliance like a moth to a light.
Pray hard to keep the light delicious.
You succumb to my bright radiance, yeah.
When you look up at the night sky, what do you see?
My shine!
Oh, you can't deny!
It's pulling you in like gravity.
You will be bowing on your knees, yeah.
Pulling you in close to me.
Watch my glory, am I following or leading the high tide?
My reign will never stop.
The time begins so right to hit the top.
Let my power ignite.
Following or leading the high tide.
I shine the brightest in the night.
And the way the waves come down...
It's pulling me in
Like gravity
You will be bowing down on your knees
I'm pulling your way
Close to me
Watch while I glorify my flow and follow me
Like a high tide
My reign will never stop
I've been waiting for so long
It is the time
Let my power ignite
Following be like a high tide
覚醒
現る黒い空
Awakening
The black sky appears
鼓動は雷鳴を繰り返す
My heartbeat repeats like thunder
嵐が来る前に
Before the storm comes
今宵はあの歌を授けましょう
Tonight, I shall bestow that song upon you
Mahari Yuware Gayae Sadunara
Amara Dirahi Jumagi Ganasala
蘇らせるのさ
I will bring it back to life
愛する君の心
Your heart, which I love
体を脱ぎ捨てて
Cast off your body
今我に返るとき
Now is the time to return to yourself
Mahari Yuware Gayae Sadunara
Amara Dirahi Jumagi Ganasala
Oh yeah...
手に放て 覚醒
Release it into your hands: Awakening
目をつぶって
Close your eyes
風をすくって
Scoop up the wind
身を溶かして
Melt your body
鐘を鳴らして
Ring the bell
Mahari Yuware Gayae Sadunara
Amara Dirahi Jumagi Ganasala
ジュマゲ・ガシャラマハリ
Jyumage Gasharamahari
イワレ・ガヤ・サバラ・アマレ
Iware Gaya Sabara Amare
ディラヒ・ジュマゲ・ガシャ
Dirahi Jyumage Gasha
ジュマゲ・ガシャラマハリ
Jyumage Gasharamahari
イワレ・ガヤ・サバラ・アマレ
Iware Gaya Sabara Amare
ディラヒ・ジュマゲ・ガシャ
Dirahi Jyumage Gasha
ジュマゲ・ガシャラマハリ
Jyumage Gasharamahari
イワレ・ガヤ・サバラ・アマレ
Iware Gaya Sabara Amare
ディラヒ・ジュマゲ・ガシャ... Oh yeah!
Dirahi Jyumage Gasha... Oh yeah!
天に吠えて
Howl to the heavens
覚醒
Awakening
雷鳴は
The thunder...
何度も
Over and over...
産声をあげる
Cries out its first breath
歌うのさ
I will sing
闇を超えて
Beyond the darkness
飛び出せ
Fly out!
マハリ・イワレ・ガヤ・サバラ
Mahari Iware Gaya Sabara
アマレ・ディラヒ・ジュマゲ・ガシャ
Amare Dirahi Jyumage Gasha
マハリ・イワレ・ガヤ・サバラ
Mahari Iware Gaya Sabara
アマレ・ディラヒ...
Amare Dirahi...
さあ
Now...
跡形も無いこの地で歌を
On this land with no traces left, a song...
胸を打ち震わせる感動を鳴らすように
To make the heart-trembling emotions ring out
いつか灯火が消えたとしても
Even if the flame should one day go out
人が生きるなら歌を
As long as people live, a song...
心は死なない
The heart shall not die
全てが壊れても
Even if everything breaks down
Everlasting Soul
息絶えた路上から香り出すのは
What wafts from the dead streets is...
火薬と血の匂い
The scent of gunpowder and blood
ジャスミン
Jasmine
朽ち果てたあばら家に吹き荒ぶ風
The wind blowing through the decayed shack
悲しみさえも
Even the sadness...
消えない
...won't fade away
朝が来たって降り続く雨だとしたら
If it's a rain that keeps falling even when morning comes
面影さえない あの歌
That song, with not even a trace left
今
Now...
跡形も無いこの地で歌を
On this land with no traces left, a song...
僅かでも微かでもまだ希望信じてるから
Because I still believe in hope, however slight or faint
奏でだし溢れ出すあの笑顔取り戻せるなら
If I can bring back those overflowing smiles by playing...
私の歌は止まない
My song will not stop
この声枯れるまで
Until this voice gives out
変わり果てても変わらないものがあると
That there are things that don't change even if everything else does
目を閉じ浮かべた
I closed my eyes and pictured...
あの風景
...that scenery
また共に鳴らせる心があるなら
If there are hearts that can ring out together again
何一つ無駄じゃないこの歌もこの愛も
Not a single thing is in vain—this song, this love...
虹色の伽藍堂 どこまでも響き渡っても
Even if the rainbow-colored void echoes forever
今はただ虚しいだけ
Now, it's just empty...
でも願いを込めて
...but I'll put my wishes into it
羊の皮を被ったものが
Those wearing sheep's clothing
羊の主役 どこまでも
Are the lead actors of the sheep, forevermore
さあ
Now...
跡形も無いこの地で歌を
On this land with no traces left, a song...
ただ強く尚強くまだ希望信じてるから
Simply stronger, still stronger, because I still believe in hope
奏でだし溢れ出すあの笑顔取り戻せるなら
If I can bring back those overflowing smiles by playing...
私の歌は止まない
My song will not stop
この声枯れるまで
Until this voice gives out
滅びたこの街で
In this ruined city
Rising soul!
ふぁー！ありがとう！
Phew! Thank you!
ふぅー...
Phew...
いや、ここまで駆け足でたくさんの歌を聴いていただきましたが...
Well, we've gone through a lot of songs at a quick pace so far...
みんな、楽しんでますかー！
Is everyone having a good time!?
わためはむちゃくちゃ楽しいです！
Watame is having a whole lot of fun!
いや本当に、歌を歌わせてくれてありがとうございます。
Really, thank you so much for letting me sing.
そしてなんと、次の曲でラストになります。
And believe it or not, the next song will be the last one.
さびしー、さびしー！
It's so sad, so sad!
さびしー！
It's so sad!
本当に寂しいんかってね。
Is she really that sad, you wonder?
いや寂しいけど、ここで嬉しい告知があります！
Well, I'm sad, but I have some happy news here!
今から歌わせていただく曲は、
The song I'm about to sing...
わためが作詞をした新曲「Revival」という曲です。
...is a new song I wrote the lyrics for, titled "Revival."
そして、わためのセカンドライブでお披露目をした、
And, "Mayday Mayday feat. Mori Calliope,"
「メーデーメーデー feat. Mori Calliope」が音源になりまして、
which premiered at my 2nd live, has been recorded...
「Revival」と一緒に、このあと24時、24時から楽曲配信されます！
...and together with "Revival," it will be released digitally at 24:00 tonight!
「Revival」と「メーデーメーデー feat. Mori Calliope」、
"Revival" and "Mayday Mayday feat. Mori Calliope,"
ぜひ買ってください！よろしくお願いします！
please be sure to get them! Thank you!
では、歌うか。寂しいけど。
Well then, shall I sing? Even though it's sad.
みんなに聴いてもらいたい新曲、
I'd like to sing the new song...
魂を込めて歌いたいと思います。
...I want everyone to hear, with all my soul.
それでは、聴いてください。新曲「Revival」。
Well then, please listen. New song: "Revival."
Revival
作詞：角巻わため　作曲・編曲：Junky
Lyrics: Tsunomaki Watame / Music & Arrangement: Junky
壊したい衝動
An impulse to destroy
崩れてく感情
Crumbling emotions
彩、失った眼光
Eyes that lost their color
突きつける銃口
A gun pointed at me
マジメな者が馬鹿を見る世界
A world where the serious ones are made to look like fools
全てを僕から奪って
Taking everything away from me
どうしてアイツは見下し笑うの？
Why does that guy look down and laugh?
叫んだ怒号も届かない
Even the shouts I screamed don't reach
泣き叫んで 泣き喚いて 救いを求めて
Crying out, wailing, seeking salvation
切り裂いて 振り払って 絡まる糸を解いて
Cutting through, shaking off, untangling the intertwined threads
囚われて 縛られて 消えない痛みに
Trapped, bound, in pain that won't fade
その手で抱きしめて 生きる意味を教えて
Hold me with those hands and tell me the meaning of life
本当は愛したいな
Truth is, I want to love
この胸を焦がすほど
Enough to set this chest ablaze
夢を笑われても 努力否定されても
Even if my dreams are laughed at, even if my efforts are denied
踏みつけられても
Even if I'm trampled upon
(笑って 笑って)
(Laugh, laugh)
何が正解など 僕にはわからないよ
What is correct, I don't really know
感情なんてもういらないよ
I don't need things like emotions anymore
涙など枯れ果てて この世を憎んで
Tears have all dried up, hating this world
噛みついて 傷つけて 赤い瞳に映して
Biting, hurting, reflecting in red eyes
記憶して 刻み込んで 消えない痛みを
Remembering, carving in, the pain that won't fade
ねえもう誰でもいい 生きる意味を教えて 今
Hey, anyone is fine, tell me the meaning of life, now
微かに聞こえる声
A faint voice that can be heard
闇を...
Through the darkness...
切り裂く声
A piercing voice
さぁ今
Now
一歩を踏み出せ
take that first step
重くても
Even if it's heavy,
辛くても
even if it's painful,
もう一度 立ち上がれ
stand up once again
駆け抜けて 手を伸ばして
Run through and reach out,
光を求めて
seeking the light
大丈夫 少しずつ
It's okay, bit by bit,
ありのままの1/1で
being your true 1/1 self
転んでも 這い上がって
Even if you fall, crawl back up,
夜に呑まれても
even if you're swallowed by the night
流した涙さえ
Even the tears you've shed
力に変えていく
will turn into your strength
この命
This life,
燃え上がれ
burn bright
僕はまだ
I'm not...
終わりじゃない
...finished yet
何度でも 何度でも
Over and over again,
僕だけの
my very own...
人生を 始めよう
life, let's begin
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
生誕祭ライブ、いかがだったでしょうか？
How did you like my birthday concert?
楽しんでもらえていたら嬉しいです。
I hope you all enjoyed it.
ここで、いくつか告知をさせてください。
Now, I have a few announcements to make.
角巻わための新曲『Revival』がこのあとすぐ、
Tsunomaki Watame's new song "Revival"
わためぇちゃんねるにてMV投稿されますので、ぜひ見てください！
will have its MV posted on Watame-channel soon, so please check it out!
そして、なんとこのあと24時から楽曲配信もあります。
And, believe it or not, digital streaming starts tonight at midnight.
新曲『Revival』と『mayday,mayday feat. Mori Calliope』の2曲、
Please listen to both "Revival" and "mayday,mayday feat. Mori Calliope" a lot.
たくさん聴いてください。よろしくお願いします。
Thank you for your support!
そして、お誕生日といえば、
And speaking of birthdays...
角巻わため誕生日記念グッズが今年も出ます！
Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Celebration Merch is coming out again this year!
詳細は、こちら！
Here are the details!
まず、2層アクリルパネル。
First, the 2-layer acrylic panel.
今年もふーみママに描き下ろしていただきました。
Fuumi-mama drew a new illustration for us again this year.
君と色違いのリュックを背負って海辺デートがテーマになっております。
The theme is a seaside date, carrying a matching backpack with you.
ぜひ飾ってください。
Please put it on display!
そして、わためといろちがいのわためいとリュック！
Next, the "Watame-ito Backpack," matching mine!
色は黒で、結構大きめサイズです。
It's black and quite large in size.
だけど軽い！ので使いやすいかなと思います。
But it's light! So I think it'll be easy to use.
そして、わためいとリュックに付けるなり、痛バにしたりできる缶バッジ！
And button badges to put on the backpack or your "ita-bag"!
4種類1セットとなっております。
They come in a set of four.
どれも可愛いので、ぜひ身の回りのものに付けてください。
They're all cute, so please pin them on your things.
さらに、わためのほっぺむにむにキーホルダー！
Furthermore, the "Watame Squishy Cheek Keyring"!
ほっぺをつつかれているわためがキーホルダーになります。
A keyring of Watame having her cheeks poked.
ぜひリュックとかに付けてもらえると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you could put it on your backpack!
フルセットで購入していただいた方には、直筆サイン＆直筆メッセージ入り
For those who buy the full set, you'll get a postcard with
ポストカードと特典ボイスが付いてきます。
a handwritten signature and message, plus bonus voice tracks.
なんと、数量制限なしで書かせていただきますので、
And I'll be signing them without any quantity limits!
みんな、どしどし買ってください！
So please, go ahead and get yours!
いろいろ告知をさせていただきましたが、
I've made a lot of announcements, but...
このあとすぐメン限ライブもやりますので、ぜひ見に来てください。
...I'm doing a members-only concert right after this, so come watch!
みんなが支えてくれているおかげで、今年もいろいろなことに挑戦できています。
Thanks to your support, I'm able to take on many new challenges this year too.
ずっと応援してくれているわためいとも、
To the Watame-itos who have always supported me,
今日初めて知ってくださった方も、
and to those who just discovered me today...
8才になったわためを、これからもどうぞよろしくお願いいたします。
Now that I've turned 8, please continue to support me.
では、メン限ライブの準備をしてくるので、
Alright, I'm going to get ready for the members-only concert...
みんな待っててね！またあとでねー！
...so please wait for me! See you later!